qmul.ac.uk 2019-03-31

# Privacy and cookies - Queen Mary University of London

## About this notice

This privacy notice explains how [Queen Mary University of London](http://www.qmul.ac.uk/contact/) (QMUL) collects [personal data](http://www.arcs.qmul.ac.uk/governance/information-governance/data-protection/dp-glossary/) via this website and how we use it and about cookies used on this site. It applies to information we collect about:

  * visitors to our websites
  * people who request a prospectus, send an enquiry, register to attend an event or apply online

## What information do we collect and how do we use it?

When someone visits our websites we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. This is to help us analyse visitor behaviour patterns and track visitor numbers so that we can monitor how it is used and improve it. We collect this information in a way which does not personally identify those using our websites. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will make this clear and will explain what we intend to do with it. You can find more information at: <http://www.arcs.qmul.ac.uk/governance/information-governance/data-protection>  You can control how we market to you by using the unsubscribe link in any email you receive or by following the instructions in any other marketing communications you may receive. Please note that some sites related to QMUL may collect and use data differently. These sites will have a local privacy notice.

## How we collect your personal data

While using this website to request a prospectus, book an event or open day, send an enquiry or apply online, you may have to submit personal data about you, which may include your name, contact details and areas of QMUL you are interested in. We are committed to protecting your privacy and the information that you give us will be processed in accordance with our [Data Protection Policy](http://www.arcs.qmul.ac.uk/media/arcs/policyzone/Data-Protection-Policy-v03.0.pdf), this statement and the privacy notice communicated to you at the point of collection. The information supplied by you will be used for specified purposes, for example to fulfil the order or booking you have made, process your application, contact you and compile statistics.

For more information, please refer to our [Central Privacy Notice](https://www.qmul.ac.uk/privacy/) and local privacy notices available to you.

## The basis for processing your personal data

When you provide personal data via our website you will provide consent for us to process that data for the purpose described. In some circumstances, the processing will be necessary for the performance of a contract or to take steps prior to entering in to a contract. Where IP addresses are logged, the legal basis is our legitimate interest in providing a website that functions effectively for all users.

## Sharing your personal data

We do not sell or share your personal data with any third parties, except where this may be permitted or required by law or where you have given consent. However, we do work with a number of third parties who act as service providers and data processors on our behalf. These are bound by contracts to process personal data securely. Submitting personal data via an online form hosted by one of these may result in data being processed outside the EEA and cookies being set by that party.

## How long your personal data is kept

We will retain your information in line with our [Records Retention Schedule](http://www.arcs.qmul.ac.uk/governance/information-governance/records-management/records-retention-schedule/). The retention period could differ depending on your relationship with us and the interactions you have with us.

## Use of cookies by Queen Mary

Cookies are small text files placed on a website visitor's computer or device, which identify it to our server. Cookies do not identify individual users, only the computer used. They are widely used in order to make websites work more efficiently, as well as to provide certain information to the owners of the site.

You may delete and block all cookies from this site. Most web browsers allow some control of cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them from your computer, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Please see the table below for details of the cookies we use at QMUL and their purpose.

**Cookie**

| 

**Name**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Expires** **  
** (you may control these through your browser settings)

| 

**More information**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utma

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

2 years

| 

| 

_utmb

| 

30 minutes  
  
| 

_utmc 

| 

On closing browser  
  
| 

_utmz

| 

6 months  
  
QM Cookie notice display

| 

QMhasVisited

| 

Signifies you have responded to our website's cookie notification banner. If you remove this cookie, the notification will display again.

| 

1000 days

|   
  
To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

## YouTube videos

We embed videos from our YouTube channels using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit [YouTube's embedding videos information page](http://support.google.com/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780).

## External links

Our websites may contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please read these policies before you submit any personal data to these third party sites.

### Your rights and further information

For further information, including on your rights, please see <https://www.qmul.ac.uk/privacy/>

## Contact us

If you have any questions or concerns please contact the Data Protection Officer by email: [data-protection@qmul.ac.uk](mailto:data-protection@qmul.ac.uk),   or post: Data Protection Officer, Queen Mary University of London, Mile End Road, London, E1 4NS
